Scoville Family Collection MS001 MS001
Cornwall Historical Society
Scoville Family Collection
1886-1925
Cornwall Historical Society
Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
MS001
0.5 Linear Feet
The Scoville family were long-time Cornwall residents who taught and farmed in Cornwall, as well as other places. Cornwall Historian E.C. Starr compiled this collection of materials by and about the Scovilles.
Provenance
This collections was compiled by Cornwall historican E.C. Starr.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Biographical / Historical
The collection consists of materials relating to the Scoville family collected by Cornwall historian E.C. Starr. Specifically, the collection is devoted to Reverend Samuel Scoville (1834-1902), his children, Annie Beecher Scoville (1866-1953), Samuel Scoville, Jr (1872-1950), and William Herbert Scoville (1873-1943), as well as their cousin, Samuel Rogers Scoville (1866-unknown).
Reverend Samuel Scoville was born in Cornwall, but spent the majority of his life presiding over churches in Vinland, New Jersey, Stamford, Connecticut, and Brooklyn, New York. Annie Beecher Scoville was a graduate of Wellesley College and teacher at several schools, including the Hampton Institute. She worked as an anthropologist among Native American tribes in the West, and owned a summer home in North Cornwall. Most of the items in the collection relating to Annie Beecher Scoville consist of articles she wrote concerning Native Americans in The Southern Workman, the school journal of the Hampton Institute. One of her brothers, Samuel Scoville, Jr., worked as a writer, and another, William Herbert Scoville, also worked as a teacher at the Hampton Institute and summered in Cornwall. Samuel Rogers Scoville resided in Cornwall, where he operated a distinguished dairy farm.
Scope and Contents
The materials in this collection have been organized into series by person. With few exceptions the content of the materials consist of publications by or about Reverend Samuel Scoville, Annie Beecher Scoville, Samuel Scoville Jr., William Herbert Scoville, and Samuel Rogers Scoville.
Cornwall (Conn.)--History.; Dairy farming--United States--History; Dairy farms -- Connecticut; Hampton Institute.; Indians of North America; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941; Scoville, Samuel, Reverend, 1834-1902; Scoville, Annie Beecher, 1866-1953; Scoville, Samuel, Junior, 1872-1950; Scoville, William Herbert, 1873-1943; Scoville, Samuel Rogers, 1866-1927; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
- Series 1. Reverend Samuel Scoville
  - Addresses given at Yale alumni meetings, 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr regarding publications, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Items relating to Henry Ward Beecher, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Obituary, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorial poem, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Image, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program for memorial window dedication in Cornwall First Congregational Church, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Annie Beecher Scoville
  - Articles in The Southern Workman, 1896-1904 (Box 1, Folder 10-22)
  - Miscellaneous journal articles by A. B. Scoville, 1896; , undated (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - Notice for lecture given by A. B. Scoville, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with E. C. Starr, undated (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- Series 3. Samuel Scoville, Jr.
  - Journal articles, 1908-1916 (Box 1, Folder 28-32)
  - Poem, "Fringed Gentleman,", 1902 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter sent to E. C. Starr, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Series 4. Samuel Rogers Scoville
  - Honorary Agricultural Recognition for S. R. Scoville, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper article, "One of the Good Farmers,", 1925 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Series 5. William Herbert Scoville
  - "The Tuskegee Negro Conference,"The Southern Workman, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 37)